Guide to the James Merrill Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
James Merrill papers
1944-2015
YCAL MSS 580
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
34.35
(58 boxes) + 1 broadside, 4 art, 1 record album storage
The collection consists of writings, correspondence, photographs, audiovisual material, artwork, printed material, computer disks and other papers by or relating to James Merrill and documenting aspects of his work as a poet and writer. Some of the material was created and accumulated by J. D. McClatchy, who served as executor of Merrill's estate and who co-edited several volumes of Merrill's works, including Collected Poems (2001), Collected Novels and Plays (2002), Collected Prose (2004), The Changing Light at Sandover (2006), and Selected Poems (2008).
Merrill, James, 1926-1995
McClatchy, J. D., 1945-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of J. D. McClatchy, 1991-2015, and purchased from Glenn Horowitz Bookseller, Inc. on the Ezra Pound Archive Fund, 2006.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 2, 19-22, 23-25 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 49, 54, 64 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Associated Materials
Other material by or relating to James Ingram Merrill (various call numbers) can be found by searching the Uncataloged Acquisitions Database and Orbis (Yale's Online Catalog).
James Ingram Merrill (1926-1995)
James Ingram Merrill was born in New York City on March 3, 1926, and grew up in Manhattan and Southampton. He received his B.A. from Amherst College in 1947. His books of poetry include: First Poems (1951); Nights and Days (1966), which won the National Book Award in Poetry; Braving the Elements (1972), for which he won the Bollingen Prize; Divine Comedies (1976), for which he won the Pulitzer Prize; Mirabell (1978), which won the National Book Award in Poetry; and The Inner Room (1988), for which he won the first Bobbitt National Prize for Poetry awarded by the Library of Congress. His other published works include essays, novels, plays, and a memoir, A Different Person (1993). Merrill died of a heart attack on February 6, 1995.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of writings, correspondence, photographs, audiovisual material, artwork, printed material, computer disks and other papers by or relating to James Merrill and documenting aspects of his work as a poet and writer. Some of the material was created and accumulated by J. D. McClatchy, who served as executor of Merrill's estate and who co-edited several volumes of Merrill's works, including Collected Poems (2001), Collected Novels and Plays (2002), Collected Prose (2004), The Changing Light at Sandover (2006), and Selected Poems (2008).
Arrangement
Organized into eight groupings: I. December 1991 Acquisition. II. February 1992 Acquisition. III. July 2006 Acquisition. IV. October 2007 Acquisition. V. October 2009 Acquisition. VI. December 2010 Acquisition. VII. October 2013 Acquisition. VIII. November 2015 Acquisition.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time.
Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with and/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. For instance, writings can be found in all six groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
Researchers should also note that similar material can be arranged differently in each acquisition, depending on how the material was organized when it was received by the library.
American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Audiotapes; Audiovisual materials; Born digital; Electronic documents; Photographic prints; Videotapes; McClatchy, J. D., 1945-; Merrill, James, 1926-1995
- December 1991 Acquisition, 1951-1991; 1; 1.08; (3 boxes)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of J. D. McClatchy, 1991.
  Arrangement
  Organized under the following headings: Writings by Merrill, Writings by Others, Correspondence, and Other Papers.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 2 (audiotapes): Use of original audiovisual material is restricted. Reference copies of may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Scope and Contents
  This portion of the collection includes writings, correspondence, and other papers by, to, or relating to James Merrill. Included are Japan: Prose of Departures, typescript, photocopy; musical adaptations of portions of Water Street; individual poems, including Bronze, typescript, photocopy; audiocassettes; transcripts of interviews; clippings; and a typed letter from Mary McCarthy to James Merrill, photocopy, 1965 Jan.
  General note
  Formerly classed as: Uncat ZA MS 212
  - Writings by Merrill
    - [The Black Swan and Other Poems,] microfilm, printed version, [undated] (Box 1)
    - Braving the Elements, book reviews, photocopies, 1973 (Box 1)
    - The Country of a Thousand Years of Peace, book reviews, photocopies, 1959 (Box 1)
    - A Different Person, first draft, typescript, photocopy, 1990-1991 (Box 1)
    - A Different Person, Chapter XIV, typescript, original, [1990] (Box 1)
      With: Autograph note from [James Merrill] to J. D. McClatchy, 1990 June 8
    - Divine Comedies, book reviews, photocopies, 1976-1979 (Box 1)
    - Divine Poem, typescript, photocopy, with pencil annotation, undated (Box 1)
    - The Fire Screen, book reviews, photocopies, 1971 (Box 1)
    - First Poems, book review, photocopy, 1951 (Box 1)
    - The Inner Room, typescript, original, undated (Box 1)
      With: The Poetry Center of the 92nd Street Y. "Marianne Moore at 100: A Centenary Reading" program, 1987 November 16
    - The Inner Room, book reviews, photocopies, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Japan: Prose of Departures, typescript, photocopy, undated (Box 1)
    - Mirabell: Books of Number, book review, photocopy, undated (Box 1)
    - Mirabell: Books of Number, book review by Robert Shaw, typescript, corrected, photocopy, undated (Box 1)
    - Nights and Days, book review, photocopy, 1966 (Box 1)
    - The Seraglio, preface, typescript, original, corrected, undated (Box 1)
    - The Seraglio, book review, photocopy, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Two Poems, book review, photocopy, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Voices from Sandover, typescript, photocopy, corrected. [Play adapted from the work by James Merrill by an unidentified author], undated (Box 1)
      With: Autograph note, signed, to J. D. McClatchy from "Peter", undated
    - Voices from Sandover, reading announcements, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
    - Water Street, book reviews, photocopies, 1963 (Box 1)
    - [Untitled speech,] typescript, photocopy, undated (Box 1)
    - Poems (Box 1)
      - "After the Ball," typescript, photocopy, undated
      - "An Upset," typescript, photocopy, undated
      - "Bronze," typescript, original and photocopy, corrected, with holograph notes and related material, undated
      - "Burnt Norton," printed version, annotated in an unidentified hand, photocopy, undated
      - "Channel 13," typescript, photocopy, undated
      - "Days of 1941 and '44," typescript, photocopy, undated
      - "Domestic Architecture," typescript, photocopy, annotated, undated
      - "From the Cutting Room Floor," typescript, photocopy, corrected, with a note to J. D. McClatchy from [James Merrill], undated
      - "H. P. (1925-80)," typescript, photocopy, undated
      - "Letter," typescript, photocopy, annotated, undated
      - "Losing the Marbles," typescript, photocopy, undated
      - "Monday Morning," typescript, photocopy, corrected, undated
      - "Mottetti VII," printed version, photocopy, annotated, 1982
      - "My Father's Irish Setters," typescript, photocopy, undated
      - "Nine Lives," typescript, corrected, photocopy, undated
      - "164 East 72nd Street," typescript, photocopy, 2 copies, undated
      - "Peter," typescript, photocopy, undated
      - "Rescue," typescript, photocopy, undated
      - "Walks in Rome," typescript, original, undated
      - Untitled poem, typescript, photocopy, corrected, undated
    - Afterward, [final draft,] typescript, photocopy, corrected, undated (Box 2)
    - Untitled manuscript, 45 poems, typescript, photocopy, bound, undated (Box 2)
      Laid in: "A Day on the Connecticut River," typescript, photocopy; "The Dresden Doll," typescript, photocopy; "Grace," typescript, photocopy; "The Illustrations," typescript, photocopy; "Midsummer Evening on the Prinsengracht," typescript, photocopy; "Month," typescript, photocopy; "The Parnassians," typescript, photocopy; "Pipe Dream," typescript, photocopy; "Santo," typescript, photocopy; "Sentimental Colloquy," typescript, photocopy; "Spell," typescript, photocopy undated
    - Untitled essay, typescript, photocopy, corrected, 1979 (Box 2)
    - Untitled essay, typescript, photocopy, undated (Box 2)
    - Untitled work, typescript, undated (Box 2)
      With: Autograph note to unidentified from James Merrill, undated
    - Fragments, typescript and holograph, undated (Box 2)
  - Writings by others
    - Eliot, T. S. Four Quarters, printed version, photocopy, annotated, undated (Box 2)
    - Hess, Marjorie. Mirabell: Books of Number. A Masque on James Merrill's Eponymous Poem to Music by Marjorie Hess, typescript, photocopy, undated (Box 2)
      With: Autograph note to J. D. McClatchy from Marjorie Hess, undated
    - Kurtzman, Jonathan. Untitled essay, typescript, photocopy, 1977 September (Box 2)
    - Librett, Jeff. "Precipitants With No Solution or My, Oh Maya! Reactions to James Merrill's 'The Book of Ephraim,'" typescript, photocopy, annotated by J. D. McClatchy, undated (Box 2)
    - Schneider, Marie. "The Personas of a Poet: James Merrill," typescript, photocopy, annotated by J. D. McClatchy, 1977 December (Box 2)
    - Sedgewick, E. K. "The 1001 Seances," typescript, photocopy, undated (Box 2)
      With: Autograph note, signed, from "Joe" to J. D. McClatchy, undated
    - Spiegelman, Willard. "James Merrill: biographical sketch," printed version, inscribed to J. D. McClatchy by the author, undated (Box 2)
    - Taylor, Jane."The Improvement of the Line: The Death and Rebirth of Communication in 'The Book of Ephraim,'" typescript, photocopy, annotated by Jane Taylor., 1978 May (Box 2)
    - Yenser, Stephen. "The Fullness of Time: James Merrill's 'Book of Ephraim,'" printed version, photocopy, undated (Box 2)
  - Correspondence
    - McCarthy, Mary. Typescript letter, signed, to [James Merrill], photocopy, 1965 January 27 (Box 2)
    - Wilson, Robert A. Typescript letter, signed, to "Jack", photocopy, 1987 January 13 (Box 2)
      With: Phaedra, theater program, photocopy, undated
  - Other papers
    - Audiocassettes, James Merrill, 1979 December 11; (2 items) (Box 2)
    - Clippings, miscellaneous, 1956-1982,undated (Box 2)
    - "PIP/Interview, James Merrill and J. D. McClatchy, transcript, Cassette 1, Side I," typescript, photocopy, corrected, undated (Box 2)
    - [Paris Review interview:] transcript, typescript, original, corrected, 1979 December (Box 2)
    - Interview with James Merrill, typescript, original, annotated (Box 2)
      With: photocopy, 1979 December 11
    - "Swimming by Night," music by Bruce Saylor, lyrics by James Merrill, [holograph], 1976 (Box 3 (Oversize))
    - Bruce Saylor, "Five Old Favorites For Medium Voice, Flute, and Piano." Poems by James Merrill, [holograph] sheet music., 1983 (Box 3 (Oversize))
      Inscribed to J. D. McClatchy by Bruce Saylor,1989 May. Annotated by James Merrill with: Autograph letter, signed, to J. D. McClatchy by Bruce Saylor 1989 May 10 and calender of performances by Constance Brown, 1989 Spring
    - "Songs From South Water Street," music by Bruce Saylor, lyrics by James Merril [holograph], [1976] (Box 3 (Oversize))
      Inscribed to J. D. McClatchy by Bruce Saylor, 1980 September 10.
- February 1992 Acquisition, undated; 2; 0.42; (1 box)
  This portion of the collection includes a typescript of A Different Person in two volumes, containing parts I-XI and XII-XXII by James Merrill.
  Gift of J. D. McClatchy, 1992.
  Formerly classed as Uncat ZA MS 218
  - A Different Person, typescript, bound in two volumes, undated; 2 (Box 4)
- July 2006 Acquisition, 1944-2004; 3; 20.55; (31 boxes) + 1 broadside, 3 art, 1 record album storage
  Box 19-21, 23-25 (audiovisual material): Use of original audiovisual material is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 22 (audio reels): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  This portion of the collection includes writings, correspondence, audivisual material, photographs, artwork and other papers by or relating to James Merrill.
  Purchased from Glenn Horowitz Bookseller, Inc. on the Ezra Pound Archive Fund, 2006.
  Formerly classed as: Uncat MSS 885
  - Merrill's correspondence
    - Harry Ford (Box 5)
    - Yukio Mishima (Box 5)
    - [unsorted], 2 (Box 5)
    - Cards with poems and notes (Box 5)
  - Writings
    - "The Book of Ephraim" (Box 5)
    - A Different Person (Box 5)
    - [ A Different Person ], The Birthday (Box 5)
    - "The Illustrations" (Box 5)
    - The Immortal Husband, 2 (Box 5)
    - Mirabell [typescripts photocopy] (Box 5)
    - "Month" (Box 5)
    - Poems, 1944 (Box 5)
    - "Scenes from Another Life" (Box 5)
    - "Scripts for the Pageant" (Box 5)
    - "The Thousand and Second Night," typescript (mimeograph) (Box 5)
    - "Tribute to Elizabeth Bishop," typescript, corrected (Box 5)
    - "III for Sandy" (Box 5)
    - Recitative, typescript, 2 (Box 5)
    - A Scattering of Salts (Box 5)
    - "Scenes from Another Life" (Box 5)
    - Merrill's thesis on Proust (Box 5)
    - "Tithonus," typescript (mimeograph). JM's mother's copy (Box 5)
    - The (Diablos) Notebook, Mary McCarthy's bound galley (Box 5)
    - The Bait, typescript carbon (Box 5)
    - Drafts [unsorted poems] (Box 5)
    - JM's poems [unsorted copies of writings and related material], 4 (Box 5)
  - Galleys, drafts, etc.
    - Collected Novels and Plays
      - Master first pass, 2002 Mar 27; 5 (Box 6)
      - Master second pass, 2002 May 24; 5 (Box 6)
      - Dead matter, 2002; 8 (Box 6)
      - Dead matter, 2002; 7 (Box 7)
      - Master Final Pass, 2002 Aug 12; 5 (Box 7)
      - [undated, 2002] [undated, 2002], 5 (Box 7)
    - Collected Poems
      - Author's set, 2000; 12 (Box 8)
      - 2000 September 12 2000 September 12, 4 (Box 8)
      - 2000 September 12 2000 September 12, 2 (Box 9)
      - 2000 November 28 2000 November 28, 8 (Box 9)
    - Collected Prose
      - 2004 May 14 2004 May 14, 6 (Box 9)
      - [undated] [undated] (Box 9)
      - [undated] [undated], 15 (Box 10)
    - The Changing Light of Sandover
      - Master draft, first pass (Box 10)
      - Master draft, first pass, 4 (Box 11)
      - Master draft, second pass, 6 (Box 11)
      - [undated] [undated], 6 (Box 11)
  - Ouija board transcripts
    - Spiral-bound notebook with Ouija Board session transcripts, and drafts of poems and essays, circa 1983 (Box 12)
    - Page of Ouija Board session inscribed to JMcC by JM and David Jackson (Box 12)
    - Ouija Board pages (Box 12)
  - Notebooks, calendars, etc.
    - Engagement calendar, 1963 (Box 12)
    - MS notebook, including poems, "Matinees," and "To My Greek", 1967 (Box 12)
    - [unidentified notebook and notepad], 2 (Box 12)
    - [blank notebook] (Box 12)
  - Other papers
    - Material relating to JM and JM's writing, 14 (Box 12)
    - Material relating to JM and JM's writing, 18 (Box 13)
    - Material relating to JM and JM's writing, 18 (Box 14)
    - Material relating to JM and JM's writing, 13 (Box 15)
    - Interview with JM for Paris Review, typescript and proof (Box 15)
    - "Letter to Freddy," by Paul Bowles and Gertrude Stein, inscribed to JM by Arthur Gold and Robert Fizdale (Box 15)
    - Music sheets (Box 15)
    - Music copybooks, 2 (Box 15)
    - Comments for JM's birthday book [photocopy] (Box 15)
    - "A Tribute to James Merrill" (Box 15)
    - "Vacances a Parigi," program (Box 15)
    - [Photograph of portrait of JM] (Box 15)
    - Legal and business papers, 4 (Box 16)
    - Material relating to JM's literary estate including JDMcC's correspondence, contracts, etc., 1995-2006; 9 (Box 16)
    - Unsorted papers, undated (Box 16)
    - The Medusa, including "Four Poems" by JM, printed, 1946 (Box 16)
    - From the Cutting Room Floor, printed, 1983 (Box 16)
    - The New Yorker and Artists' Theatre: Four Plays, printed, 1960, 1993-1995 (Box 16)
    - [Miscellaneous printed material], 12 (Box 17)
    - [Miscellaneous artwork], 4 (Box 17)
    - [Crossword puzzle book, annotated and illustrated by JM] (Box 17)
    - Material removed from printed volumes (Box 17)
    - [Photographs], 3 (Box 17)
    - Carl Van Vechten's photograph of Claude Frederico, 1947 (Box 17)
  - Awards
    - National Book Critics' Circle Award, 1983 (Box 17)
    - National Institute of Arts & Letters membership certificate, 1971 (Box 17)
    - Pulitzer Prize, 1977 (Box 17)
  - Photographs
    - [Unidentified,] 35mm photographic negatives (Box 18)
  - Audiovisual material
    - Audiocassettes
      Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - James Merrill tribute, 1995 May 13, 2 (Box 19)
      - AC class day, 1980 May 24 (Box 19)
      - Bruce Saylor (Box 19)
      - The Academy of American Poets Audio Archive (Box 19)
      - Service for James Merrill, 1995 Feb 13 (Box 19)
      - James Merrill: Morgan Reading, 1988 Dec 1 (Box 19)
      - James Merrill, Sunken Party Festival, Hill-Stead Museum, 1993 June (Box 19)
      - "An Upward Look", 2 (Box 19)
      - Merrill reading for his work, introduction by Holly Hall, 1994 Nov 19 (Box 19)
      - JM reading section 2 of Ephraim and Mirabell (Box 19)
      - Scripts for the Pageant, 4 (Box 19)
      - The Academy of American Poets Audio Archive, Richard Wilbur (Box 19)
      - Scripts for the Pageant, 4 (Box 20)
      - JM reading "Ephraim". Side 1: A-F (midway) and Side 2: F-K, undated; 1 (Box 20)
        Reformatting
        YCALMSS580_0001
      - JM reading "Ephraim". Side 1: K-Q and Side 2: Q-Y, undated; 1 (Box 19)
        Reformattin
        YCALMSS580_0002
        On the cassette, sides 1 and 2 are identified as sides 3 and 4. The cassette is a continuation of the previous cassette.
      - Poets in Person, James Merrill and Adrienne Rich, 1991 (Box 20)
      - Elizabeth Bishop, Voices & Visions, 1996 (Box 20)
      - "The Classic Hundred Poems" (Box 20)
      - JM reading "Mirabell", 3 (Box 20)
      - [unidentified] (Box 20)
    - Compact Disks
      - Songs of Lee Hoiby (Box 21)
      - David Patterson, Saving Daylight Time (Box 21)
      - Songs by Daron Hagen (Box 21)
      - American Academy of Poets Anthology, Vol. II (Box 21)
      - The AIDS Quilt Songbook (Box 21)
    - Audio reels
      - Bridge, Good Friday, 1965 April 17, 2 (Box 22)
        Access to audio reels is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Contact Access Services for further information.
      - "Mandala" for bass/baritone and piano: poem by JM set to music by Gregory Martindale (Box 22)
    - Record Albums
      - Phaedra (Box 23 (Record album storage))
      - Voices of Haiti (Box 23 (Record album storage))
      - 13 Ways of Looking at a Blackbird (Box 23 (Record album storage))
    - Videocassettes
      Audio Visual: Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
      - JM reading sections from his poetry at the College of William and Mary, recorded, 1985 March 26 (Box 24)
      - Quay Bros., Street of Crocodiles (Box 24)
      - "Voices from Sandover, Parts 1 and 2", 1995 May 1 (Box 24)
      - Lorenzo's Oil (Box 24)
      - [unidentified] (Box 24)
      - "Voices and Visions: Wallace Stevens" (Box 24)
      - "Voices and Visions: Elizabeth Bishop" (Box 24)
      - The Poetry Center, James Merrill, 1980 April 11 (Box 24)
      - JM reading, Washington University, St. Louis, 1994 November 19 (Box 25)
      - JM reading, intro by Holly Hall. Simon Audiotrium, WU. Final evening of "James Merrill: A Life in Writing", 1994 Novmeber 19 (Box 25)
      - "James Merrill Estate", 1995 March 13; 4 (Box 25)
      - JM Funeral Service, Stonington, 1995 February 13 (Box 25)
      - Merrill Memorial, New York Public Library, 1995 May 13 (Box 25)
      - Mirabell's Book of Numbers, opera University of Wisconsin, Madison, 1993 October (Box 25)
  - Miscellaneous material
    - JM's baby shoes (Box 26)
    - Somerset Maugham's bedroom slippers given to JM (Box 26)
    - W. H. Auden's bedroom slippers given to JM (Box 26)
    - Collar and identification tag for Masie [JM's cat] (Box 26)
    - Frames [empty], 2 (Box 26)
    - Willowware tea cup used for the Ouija Board sessions that led to Sandover (Box 27)
    - Photographs, 10 (Box 28)
    - Southern Campus, David Jackson's college yearbook, 1947 (Box 29)
    - Typewriter (Box 30)
    - Suitcase (Box 31 (Art))
    - Suitcase (Box 32 (Art))
  - Oversize
    - "The Writer's Desk," calendar (Box 33 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook from Donald Richie [Summer] presented to JM and DJ, contains photographs of nude Japanese young men (Box 33 (Oversize))
    - Scrapbook of opera programs and reviews assembled by JM in 1943 with his handwritten comments (Box 33 (Oversize))
    - "Swimming by Night," music by Bruce Saylor, commissioned for J. D. McClatchy's birthday, music holograph, 1976 March 3 (Box 34 (Oversize))
    - [Miscellaneous book production material] (Box 34 (Oversize))
    - [Miscellaneous clippings and articles], 4 (Box 34 (Oversize))
    - Coat of arms artwork (Box 35 (Oversize))
    - [Miscellaneous artwork], 3 (Box 35 (Oversize))
    - [Unidentified letter] (Box 35 (Oversize))
    - Posters for Merrill reading (Box 35 (Oversize))
    - Amherst diploma (Box 35 (Oversize))
    - Yale diploma (Box 35 (Oversize))
    - Photos of Merrill, 2 (Box 35 (Oversize))
    - [Empty envelopes] (Box 35 (Oversize))
    - [Wooden cross that marked location of JM's grave] (Box 36 (Oversize))
    - Ouija board (Box 37 (Oversize))
    - National Book Award (Box 37 (Oversize))
    - Poetry in Motion posters (Box 37 (Oversize))
    - Pencil drawing of JM in Athens by David Jackson (Box 38 (Oversize))
    - Portrait photograph of JM by May Deren (Box 38 (Oversize))
    - [Sketch pad] (Box 38 (Oversize))
    - [Misc. photographs] (Box 38 (Oversize))
    - [Misc. artwork, posters, etc.], 6 (Box 38 (Oversize))
  - Oversize Folder
    - Print (Box 39 (Broadside))
  - Framed Items
    - Charcoal drawing (Box 40 (Art))
- October 2007 Acquisition, 1944-2006; 4; 5; (9 boxes) + 1 art
  Custodial History
  Gift of J. D. McClatchy, 2007.
  Box 49 (computer disks): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  This portion of the collection consists of material pertaining to James Merrill, created and accumulated by J. D. McClatchy who was executor of Merrill's estate, including drafts and proofs of Collected Poems of James Merrill (2001) and Collected Prose of James Merrill (2004), both of which were edited by J. D. McClatchy and Stephen Yenser.
  Formerly classed as: Uncat MSS 988
  - Collected Poems of James Merrill, printed (photocopy), corrected, 6 (Box 41)
  - Collected Poems of James Merrill, proof, 14 (Box 41)